字幕制作：糖葫芦@豆瓣
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (VEHICLE APPROACHES)
- (BRAKES CRANK)
（东南亚某地）
- (CELL PHONE DIAL BEEPING)
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(LINE RINGING)
NAVIN: (ON PHONE) Hey,
嘿
I fell asleep in front of
the TV waiting for you.
我等你的时候在电视机前睡着了
(CHILD SHRIEKS ON VIDEO)
NAVIN: Are you
coming home tonight?
你今晚回家吗？
Or should I just
go to bed alone?
还是我自己先睡？
MATIA: Do you remember
the noodle stand downtown?
你还记得市中心那个面摊吗？
That little street kid
heard us arguing
有一个流浪的小男孩听到我们吵架
and he kept trying to sell you
flowers to make up with me?
一直想卖花给你 好让你哄我开心的那个？
NAVIN: Yeah.
记得
MATIA: That boy
went missing a week ago.
那个男孩一周前失踪了
(NAVIN SIGHS)
（打击人口拐卖... 黎明一定会到来...）
MATIA: I'm leaving
the van near there.
我把面包车停在那附近了
NAVIN: Why?
为什么？
MATIA: I love you, Navin,
but I have to go.
我爱你 纳文 但我必须得走了
NAVIN: I haven't
seen you in days, Matia.
我好几天没见到你了 玛蒂娅
- Just come home--
-  (LINE DISCONNECTS)
跟我回家吧...
(DOOR OPENS)
（国际记者证 - 玛蒂娅）
- (DOOR SLAMS)
- (FOOTSTEPS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHILD CRYING IN DISTANCE)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
- (MATIA PANTING)
- (CRYING GROWS LOUDER)
(MATIA GASPS)
(CHILD CONTINUES CRYING)
(MATIA GRUNTS)
(SPEAKS FILIPINO) Intruder!
Intruder!
有人闯入 有人闯入
MAN: (IN ENGLISH)
Hey! She's there!
嘿 她在那边
Run!
快跑
(ALL GRUNTING)
Run! Go! Go! Go!
快跑 走 快走
(ALL GRUNTING)
(FLESH SQUELCHES)
- (ARROW WHISTLING)
- (SQUELCHES)
(THUDS)
(PANTING)
PAKLUNG: (SIGHS) What a waste.
真是浪费
That boy is dead
because of you.
那个男孩是因你而死的
Doesn't matter. I'll just pick
up another one, you know?
不过没关系 我再抓一个就是了 懂吗？
Fuck. It's late.
操 太晚了
I got to get home to my wife.
Hey, take her downstairs.
我得回家陪老婆了 嘿 把她带到楼下去
I want to know
how she got in here.
我要查清楚她是怎么进来的
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ARROW WHOOSHES)
（《火遮眼》）
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(HAMMERING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Where are you going?
你去哪儿？
I have to go to work.
You can sleep in.
我得去上班了 你再睡会儿吧
Can I go to work
with you instead?
我可以和你一起去吗？
Hello, everybody.
大家好
Summer vacation
is almost over.
暑假快要完了
My dad is working non-stop,
我爸竟然还要工作
so he can't always
keep me company.
虽然不能总陪本小姐
I'm a grown-up now,
谁叫我这么乖巧懂事
so I don't really mind.
不过我也不介意啦
Let's look at a day
in the life of a handyman.
我带大家看看爸爸工作的地方吧
Why aren't you wearing
the steel-toe boots I got you?
都不穿我给你买的那双鞋？
You never listen to me.
不听话
Here's his tool box.
这是爸爸的百宝箱
(SNAPS FINGERS THRICE)
(GASPS)
He's both talented
and handsome.
他既聪明又帅气
Hey, Dad, make a heart
with your fingers!
来 比个心
I'm going back to China
in two days.
两天过后 我就回国啦
You don't have much time left
to make finger-hearts for me.
再不比心那个就没机会啦
Come on, Dad.
来啊 爸
Watch out
for your old head injury.
小心你头上的旧伤
You're a danger to yourself.
真不会照顾自己
- (IN ENGLISH) Thank you.
- Thank you.
-谢谢 -谢谢
- Bye-bye.
-再见 -再见
(MAN SPEAKING FILIPINO) Hey!
嘿
How's business today, Auntie?
阿姨 今天生意怎么样？
- Let's take a look.
- (BANGS ON TABLE)
让我们看看
- (LAUGHS)
- Business is pretty good, huh?
生意挺好的嘛？
Stop counting
and just give it to me!
别数了 赶紧给我
Faster!
快点
(IN MANDARIN)
Bullying an old lady. It's outrageous!
那些坏人欺负老人家也太过分了吧
It's not our business.
不关我们的事
How can you survive if you're
so scared of everything?
你这么怕事儿 该怎么生活？
Dad!
爸
Maybe I shouldn't go
back home.
要不 我不回去了
I can just stay here
and help you.
留下来照顾你
Maybe Grandma and I could
move here to be with you?
我和奶奶都可以搬过来住？
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(SIGHS)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SIZZLING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(FIRE WHOOSHES)
(CHUCKLES)
(IN ENGLISH) I have good news.
我有个好消息
Found you a buyer
out of Eastport.
在东港给你找了个买家
(SLURPS) A rich one.
是个有钱人
How many?
要多少？
Thank you.
谢谢
Three's a piece of cake.
三个简直小菜一碟
Thirty.
三十个
- (SPUTTERS)
- (FIRE WHOOSHES)
I need a favor.
我需要你帮个忙
Get me a meeting
with your boss.
帮我安排跟你老板见一面
Can you do that?
你能办到吗？
(CHUCKLES, SPEAKS FILIPINO)
See you later.
回头见
NAVIN: (IN ENGLISH) See you.
回见
MAN: (ON TV) Matia Pham
alleged a connection
玛蒂娅·范声称
between numerous
kidnapping cases
多起绑架案之间存在某种关联
in a livestream
to her followers
这是她在向粉丝直播时透露的
shortly before
her disappearance
就在她失踪前不久
earlier this year.
今年早些时候
MATIA: (ON TV) The police
want to treat these cases
警方想把这些案件
like isolated incidents,
当作孤立事件处理
but if you take a step back
但如果你退一步看
to look at these families'
social and economic status,
看看这些家庭的社会和经济地位
and the neighborhoods
where these kids go missing,
以及这些孩子失踪的街区
there is an obvious pattern.
就会发现有明显的规律
I'm talking about
a coordinated effort
我想说的是 这是一次有组织的行动
to target kids
专门针对
from some of the city's
poorest communities.
本市一些贫困社区的孩子
MAN: (ON TV) Asked about
Pham's allegations,
当被问及范的指控时
- a law enforcement...
- (GROANS)
一位执法部门
...spokesperson told
our reporter that,
发言人告诉我们的记者
as a matter of policy,
出于政策规定
the agency will not comment
on ongoing investigations.
该机构不会对正在进行的调查发表评论
Coming up: A breakthrough
in renewable energy
接下来为您报道 可再生能源取得突破
that will power your home
at half the cost.
将以一半的成本为您家供电
(CLAPS)
You have to keep training.
你必须坚持训练
It's for your own good.
这是为你好
(DOOR OPENS, SLAMS)
(LOW SUSPENSEFUL
MUSIC PLAYING)
NAVIN: I have good news.
我有个好消息
Found you a buyer
out of Eastport.
在东港给你找了个买家
A rich one.
是个有钱人
（亲爱的纳文 记住 记者总是要深挖到底 玛蒂亚）
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTTLE SPRAYING)
(CLAPS)
If you cut your hair short,
you'll feel nice and cool.
如果你把头发剪短 会觉得很凉快
No! I'll look terrible.
不剪 难看死了
(WOMAN SIGHS)
(IN MANDARIN) Sweetie.
唉 小妹妹
You'll look prettier
if you cut your hair short.
头发剪短一点 会更漂亮
Remember, it's how Auntie
Mable cut your hair last time.
上次也是梅布尔阿姨帮你剪的
You'll look great.
还记得吗？
You liked having short hair
when you were little,
你小时候就喜欢留短发
and it will make
your kung fu training easier.
而且这样你练功夫也更方便
No more kung fu!
不练了
My classmates already think
I'm a tomboy.
同学都笑我假小子
No one will ever like me.
一辈子没人喜欢
I'd rather you be able to
protect yourself than be pretty.
我宁愿你能保护自己 也不要你漂亮
(RAINY SIGHS)
I can't always be around
to protect you.
我不能一直陪在你身边保护你
Exactly!
是啊
But why can't I be here
with you?
你为什么不在我身边呢？
I only practice kung fu
because we're practicing together.
我以前喜欢学功夫 是因为你会一直陪我练
I never even liked it.
其实我喜欢的不是功夫
I just want to spend time
with you.
是和你在一起
Can't you just go back
to China with me?
跟我回国去吧 好吗？
Mom died,
and you've left me, too.
妈妈死了 你也走了
Sweetie!
哎 小妹妹
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
You never loved me!
你从来没爱过我
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (BELL JINGLES)
Calm down.
哎 冷静一点
She won't listen to you
even if you chase her.
你追上去她也不会听你的
Relax, I've got
three daughters too.
放心 我也有三个女儿
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
So annoying.
讨厌 讨厌
Annoying.
讨厌
(PANTING)
Can you speak Chinese?
你会说中文吗？
My sister was hit by a car,
我妹妹在那边被车撞了
and my parents aren't home.
我爸爸妈妈都不在家
Can you help me?
你能帮帮我吗？
Where?
在哪里？
Over there.
那边
Follow me!
跟我来
My eldest daughter
always says she's busy,
我大女儿整天说忙忙忙忙忙
but she doesn't even have
a boyfriend!
结果男朋友都没一个
My second daughter--
那我二女儿呢
I can't find her!
我找不到她啊
- This way?
- Yeah. Over there.
-这边吗？ -对 就是前面
Slow down.
等一下
Is your leg okay?
你腿没事吧？
It's fine.
没事
Over there.
那边
- (GRUNTS)
- (RAINY SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES
IN DISTANCE)
- (HO GRUNTS)
- (RAINY SCREAMS)
(IN FILIPINO) Just one?
Useless.
才一个？ 没用的废物
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARES)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(IN ENGLISH) Get him inside!
把他弄里面去
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELPS)
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELPS)
(YELLING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
嘿...
Hey!
嘿
(DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(RAINY IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸爸
Dad!
(IN ENGLISH) Hey!
Grab her, idiot!
嘿 抓住她 蠢货
(RAINY SCREAMING AND SHOUTING)
Dad!
爸爸
- (SCREAMING)
- (CHUCKLES)
Dad!
爸爸
(WHEELS SCREECH)
(IN FILIPINO) Faster, faster!
快点 快点
(ENGINE REVS)
(HORN BLARES)
(PANTING)
(HORNS HONKING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
- (PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- (PANTING)
(MAN IN FILIPINO)
What's wrong with you? What's happening?
你怎么了？ 发生什么事了？
(IN ENGLISH) Sir?
You're bleeding on my counter.
先生？ 你的血滴在我的柜台上了
If you've had an accident,
如果你出了什么意外
there's a hospital
down the street.
前面街上就有一家医院
（光头大...）
"Big bald guy..."
“光头大汉”
（爆炸头男子）
（蓝色货车 车牌号：74-7533）
If you need to report a crime,
如果你需要报案
take a seat over there.
去那边坐下
Okay?
好吗？
（查监控 没时间了）
(SIGHS) There's
always time, sir.
时间总是有的 先生
Just slow down--
慢慢来...
Hey! Don't do
that again! Okay?
嘿 别再这样了 听到没？
- What's going on here?
- I don't know.
-这里出什么时候了？ -我不知道
Something about a kidnapping.
But I told him to wait.
好像是绑架案 但我叫他等一下
Come with me.
跟我来
CAPTAIN: What the hell is
going on around here?
这里到底在搞什么鬼？
Captain, this man's daughter's
been kidnapped.
队长 这个人的女儿被绑架了
He's got a license plate
and a perp description.
他有车牌号和嫌疑人特征
It doesn't look
like a report to me.
这看着可不像是报案
- (EXHALES)
- Look,
听着
we have procedures here.
我们这里有规章制度的
I'll hang on to this.
这个我就先收着
If we come over something my
guys will get a hold of you.
如果有发现线索我的人会联系你的
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
（失踪人口）
(PANTING)
（服务和保护 警察局）
(WATER DRIPPING)
(LOW FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR OPENS)
- (GASPS)
- (CLANGS)
(PANTING)
POLICEWOMAN:
No driver's license.
没有驾照
No employment history.
没有工作记录
No criminal record.
没有犯罪记录
Like he appeared
out of thin air.
就像是凭空冒出来的一样
(EXHALES)
Probably a fugitive.
可能是个逃犯
(IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸
(IN ENGLISH) Who are you?
你是谁？
(EXHALES)
(LOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- (FIGHTERS GRUNTING)
- (BELL DINGING)
- REFEREE: Stop. Stop.
停 停
(CROWD CHEERING)
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(MUFFLED CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN FILIPINO)
Hey! What's up, man?
嘿 怎么了 哥们？
What's up, man?
怎么了 哥们？
- (IN ENGLISH) Go!
- (BELL DINGS)
开始
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKERS)
- (CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- (BELL DINGING)
(IN ENGLISH) Keep the boss
in a good mood,
把老板哄开心
he'll agree to anything.
Just be cool.
他什么都会答应的 放轻松
Have a drink, enjoy the girls.
喝杯酒 好好享受这里的美女
(MAN CONTINUES SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER SPEAKERS)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS) Hey!
嘿
Get up, big boy!
起来 大个子
I brought a guest.
我带了客人来
- NAVIN: Hi.
- (HO CHUCKLES)
嗨
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Uh-oh.
哎哟
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(LAUGHING)
Hold on a minute.
等一下
You stay.
你留下
(DOOR OPENS)
- (CLUB MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (FIGHTERS GRUNTING)
- Stop!
- (BELL DINGING)
停
(MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER SPEAKERS)
Mr. Song.
宋先生
Finally, a man that might know
how to get me what I want.
总算来了个可能知道怎么满足我要求的人
- Sit.
- Thank you.
-坐 -谢谢
SONG: Ah... So...
所以...
You want...
你...
(EXHALES)
- Thirty for the weekend?
- NAVIN: Longer.
-这周末要三十个？ -时间更长些
That's some kind of
big party, huh?
那可是个大派对啊 是吧？
NAVIN: It's not a party.
Shrimp boats.
不是派对 是捕虾船
My partner does
business in Eastport.
我的合伙人在东港做生意
Thirty kids. That's, uh...
三十个孩子 那可是
Shit, that's like shipping
a fucking school bus, man.
我靠 那简直就是一整校车了 老兄...
(LAUGHS)
We understand.
我们明白
That's why we're offering you
a very good deal.
所以我们开出的价钱很高
Three times the market price.
市场价的三倍
All in cash. USD?
全付现金 美元？
All cash. USD.
全现金 美元
(CHUCKLING)
With one small
requirement, Mr. Song.
但有一个小小的要求 宋先生
I have to
hand-pick them myself.
我必须亲自挑选
Ah, that's not
gonna work, cowboy. (LAUGHS)
啊 这可不行 牛仔
Well... commercial fishing is
a competitive industry.
怎么说呢 商业捕鱼竞争很激烈
I need your best,
and I just have to make sure.
我需要你这最好的货 我只是要确认一下
So, let me get this straight.
所以 让我理清楚
You want to come...
你想来到...
to my spot, right?
我的地盘 对吧？
Shop around like it's,
uh, some fruit stand...
像挑水果一样挑肥拣瘦
and then pay me later?
(LAUGHING)
然后再付钱？
(GLASSES CLATTERING)
Who the fuck are you?
What do you want?
你他妈是谁？ 你想干什么？
- (CLUB MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
If you're a cop,
you're either new
如果你是警察 那你要么是新来的
or too stupid
to be on my payroll.
要么就是太蠢 没能被我买通
(CHUCKLES) Mr. Song...
宋先生
Let me put it this way.
我这么跟你说吧
I'm just a messenger here.
我只是个传话的
My partner's waiting for me,
我的合伙人还在等我
and you're wasting
my fucking time...
你在浪费我妈的时间
Boss.
老板
His fucking time.
他妈的时间
Your fucking time.
你妈的时间
(SCOFFS)
- Your fucking time?
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
你妈的时间？
SONG: I like you!
我喜欢你
If you want to
pick 'em, cowboy...
如果你想自己挑 牛仔
I'll take you there myself.
我亲自带你去
- Let's go!
- All right. Sit down! Party!
-我们走 -好的 坐下 接着玩
Hey, slow down there, man.
嘿 慢点 哥们
Hey, this is
a private party. Hey!
嘿 这是私人派对 嘿
Listen, buddy,
it's invitation-only up here.
听着 哥们 上面要有邀请才能进
- Turn around.
- Fuck off!
-转过去 -滚开
(CLUB MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CHUCKLES, SCOFFS) Okay...
好吧
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- (BELL DINGS)
(IN FILIPINO)
Help! Somebody grab him!
救命 快抓住他
(IN ENGLISH) Hey! Hey! Hey!
嘿...
He's got a gun!
他有枪
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Come on! You want money?
来啊 你想要钱吗？
Kill him! Go fucking kill him!
杀了他 给我杀了他
(IN FILIPINO)
Boss, there's a guy downstairs with a gun!
老板 楼下有个带枪的家伙
(IN ENGLISH) Mr. Song, that's
got nothing to do with me. I--
宋先生 这跟我没关系 我
Kill this fucker! Now!
杀了这混蛋 立刻
Mr. Song! Mr. Song!
宋先生 宋先生
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (SIGHS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GLASSES SHATTERING)
(THUGS GROANING)
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELPS)
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
(MAN COUGHING)
(SPECTATORS SHOUTING
IN FILIPINO) Kill him! Kill him!
杀了他 杀了他
Kill him! Kill him!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(FIGHTERS GRUNTING)
(BONES CRACK)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTING)
(SQUELCHING)
(SCREAMS)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(WHIMPERS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(MIC FEEDBACK WHINING)
(IN ENGLISH) Fuck!
操
Enjoy the party, asshole!
好好享受派对吧 混蛋
(PANTING)
Fucking asshole!
妈的混蛋
(SCREAMS)
(COUGHS WEAKLY)
(NECK SNAPS)
- (TYPING)
- (BEEPING)
（下载中...）
(GRUNTING)
(IN ENGLISH) Who are you?
你是谁？
Huh?
啊？
All right.
好吧
(GRUNTING)
(CRACKS NECK)
(BLOWS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLS)
NAVIN: Wait!
等等
I'm not one of them.
我跟他们不是一伙的
Okay?
好吗？
You're looking for someone.
你在找人
So am I.
我也是
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
We've gotta get out of here.
Come on!
我们得离开这里 走
- I can't give you this, okay?
- (BANGING ON DOOR)
我不能把这个给你 知道吗？
- (MAN SPEAKS FILIPINO)
They're here! Call for backup. - (BANGING CONTINUES)
他们在这儿 呼叫支援
(IN ENGLISH) But I can show
you what's on it, all right?
但我可以给你看里面的内容 行吗？
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
(LOW SUSPENSEFUL
MUSIC PLAYING)
- (DISTANT PUNCHES LANDING)
- (MAN GROANING)
- (YELLS)
- (GROANS)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
(GROANING)
You vouched for a rat.
你给一个探子做担保
(WEAKLY) Boss, please.
(GROANING)
老板 求你了
SONG: Come here, boy.
过来 孩子
Watch your father die.
看着你爸爸死
You know the drill.
Freeze this bastard.
你知道规矩 冻死这混蛋
No! I'm sorry! Boss!
不 对不起 老板
Boss, I'm sorry!
老板 对不起
(IN FILIPINO) Don't kill me!
别杀我
I didn't know who he was!
我不知道他是谁
I don't want to die!
我不想死
(SCREAMING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(BOY GROANING)
(MAN SPEAKS) In here!
下去
(DOOR CLOSES)
(IN MANDARIN)
I was just trying to help you. Why would you set me up?
我好心帮你 为什么要害我？
I'm asking you!
Why did you do that?
我问你 为什么？
Was it only because
they gave you some chocolate?
就为了这个？
You helped them
just because of this?
就为了这个 替这帮人渣骗人？
They're not going
to let you go.
你以为他们会放过你吗？
You think they'll let you
go home? Idiot!
你以为他们就会送你回家吗？ 你这个猪头
You're the idiot!
你才猪头
You faked being nice
and got yourself into trouble.
你装好心 自投罗网
It's not my fault.
关我屁事
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(IN FILIPINO) Quiet!
冷静
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Stop fighting!
别打了
(MAN SHOUTS) Stop!
住手
Don't go!
别跑
Stop!
站住
(GROANS)
(IN ENGLISH) Father said
the bad ones get punished.
爸爸说过 坏人会受到惩罚
MAN: Hey! Hey!
Enough, big guy.
嘿 够了 大块头
Your father wants them
shipped out alive.
你爸爸要他们活着运出去
You know you ruined two months
of my hard work, right?
你知道你毁了我两个月的心血吗？
At least say something.
至少说点什么吧
Enough with the quiet,
tough guy act.
别再装冷酷硬汉了
What are you?
你到底是什么人？
(CHUCKLES) A mute?
哑巴吗？
Huh? You know him?
怎么？ 你认识他？
Song picked him up young.
宋在他很小的时候就收养了他
Threw him into the ring
between rounds as a joke.
回合休息的时候把他扔进擂台当笑话看
He's a poster boy
for head trauma.
他就是脑部创伤的典型代表
(SIGHS)
This guy. Mr. Song.
这家伙 就是宋先生
You know him, too?
你也认识他？
(SIGHS)
Come with me.
跟我来
(GRUNTS) Sorry about the mess.
抱歉这里很乱
I've kinda been
living back here.
我这段时间一直住在这后面
(TAPS)
Mr. Song is the biggest
human trafficker in the city.
宋先生是这个城市最大的人口贩子
My wife is a journalist.
我的妻子是一名记者
This is everything
she's gathered
这是她目前为止收集到的
about Song's operation so far.
关于宋氏团伙运作的所有资料
She went missing
while investigating this case.
她在调查这个案子时失踪了
Her name is Matia.
她叫玛蒂娅
(SETS DOWN PHOTO)
May I?
我能看看吗？
(EXHALES)
(IN MANDARIN) "Rainy?
雨晴？
"Happy birthday, daddy."
爸爸生日快乐
(SIGHS)
（记者调查网络儿童拐卖事件 在采访后失踪）
I haven't had time
to go through
我还没来得及仔细看
everything she left behind.
她留下的所有东西
She knew Song was
organizing the kidnappings.
她知道是宋在组织绑架案
He moves the kids around
他把孩子们转移来转移去
while he checks out
potential buyers.
同时在物色潜在买家
(LOW SUSPENSEFUL
MUSIC PLAYING)
What?
怎么了？
- What is it?
- (TAPS PHOTOS)
发现什么了？
NAVIN: (EXHALES) Same truck.
同一辆卡车
(TYPING)
The refrigeration truck
makes deliveries everywhere.
这辆冷藏车到处送货
The insulation would make them
completely soundproof.
它的隔热层能让车厢完全隔音
The factory's an hour
outside the city. Come on.
工厂在城外一小时车程的地方 走吧
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(IN FILIPINO) Two bags of ice.
两袋冰块
（雪花纯净冰 冰块配送）
(SCOFFS, IN ENGLISH)
All this in plain sight.
就在大白天
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
嘿 你在干什么？
There could be
a hundred guys in there.
里面可能有一百多个人
You won't save your daughter
by being impulsive.
你这么冲动救不了你女儿的
We wait.
我们得等
（没时间了）
What do you suggest?
你有什么建议？
(TYPING)
(IN MANDARIN)
"Feint east, attack west..."
“声东击西”
(IN ENGLISH) Hey! Hey!
嘿...
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: Hey!
嘿
(IN FILIPINO)
Get the hell out of here!
给我滚出去
(MEN CLAMORING)
(CRASHING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CRACKS NECK, GRUNTS)
(IN ENGLISH)
Father says, "No trespassing."
爸爸说过 禁止擅闯
(MAN GROANING)
(MAN YELLS)
(MEN GRUNTING)
SONG: Bitch!
贱人
Die!
去死吧
What the fu--
搞什...
(GUNSHOTS)
You are in my fucking house!
你他妈在我的地盘上
(YELLS) Shit!
该死
(GRUNTING)
Eat shit and die! (LAUGHS)
吃屎 去死吧
(GUNSHOTS)
On my fucking day off.
偏偏在老子休息的时候搞这出
(WHISTLES)
(YELLS)
- (MEN GRUNTING)
- You again?
又是你？
(GUN CLICKING)
Ah, shit!
妈的
Found them?
找到了吗？
Hey!
嘿
(IN MANDARIN)
Feint east, attack west!
声东击西
(IN ENGLISH) Ah, I see you!
哈 我看到你了
(GUNSHOTS)
(SONG SCREAMS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(HO YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(RATTLING)
(EERIE VOCALIZATION PLAYS)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(THUDS)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH STRAINING)
(LOW FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(CLANGS)
(SLEDGEHAMMER SCRAPING)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GRUNTING)
(CRUNCHING)
- (THUDS)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SQUELCHING)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
(GRUNTING)
NAVIN: Enough!
够了
- (GUNSHOT)
- Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
Song's the only lead
we have left!
宋是我们唯一的线索了
Killing him won't get you
any closer to your daughter!
杀了他 也找不到你女儿
She might still be alive.
她可能还活着
- And we're getting closer.
- (GROANS)
我们会找到她的
(SCREAMS)
WOMAN: Listen close.
仔细听
You can hear
your little girl's heartbeat.
你能听到你女儿的心跳声
- (HEART BEATING)
- Have you chosen a name?
你起好名字了吗？
Um... Mirai.
It means "future."
嗯... 米莱Mirai 意思是“未来”
(MACHINE SWITCHES OFF)
- Baby Mirai...
- (MACHINE BEEPS)
小米莱
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- PAKLUNG: Oh, excuse me.
哦 不好意思
What?
怎么了？
CAPTAIN: A fight broke out
你岳父的工厂里
at your
father-in-law's factory
发生了一场斗殴
and Song's not
answering the phone.
而且宋不接电话
Sounds like that Chinese mute,
looking for his daughter.
那个中国哑巴好像在找他女儿
I'm still trying
to identify the other guy.
我还在调查另一个人的身份
The old man will want to know
how security failed.
老爷子肯定想知道安保是怎么出纰漏的
He'll want to hear it
from you. Face to face.
他想听你亲口当面解释
PAKLUNG: You all trusted me.
你们都信任我
I want you to know I take
that responsibility seriously.
我想让你们知道我把这份责任看得很重
The factory was empty.
工厂当时是空的
I'd already moved the cargo
somewhere else
我已经把货转移到其他地方了
after the break-in
at the club.
就在俱乐部被闯入之后
I mean, sure, a few men died,
我是说 没错 是死了几个人
but we didn't lose
anything of value.
但我们没损失任何有价值的东西
Your investment
remains secure.
你们的投资依然很安全
If there is
any additional expense,
如果有任何额外开销
I'll cut it
from my own earnings.
我会从我自己的收益里扣
All I want is
to do right by the family.
我只想把家族的事情做好
This fool is reckless.
这是个鲁莽的蠢货
- (ELECTRICITY BUZZING FAINTLY)
- (WATER DRIPPING)
(METAL FENCE RATTLING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- (SONG GROANING)
- (CRACKLING STOPS)
- (GASPING)
You...
你...
fucking motherfu-- (SCREAMS)
去你妈的...
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SCREAMING)
NAVIN: Hey!
嘿
(CRACKLING STOPS)
We need him awake. I got this.
我们得让他醒着 交给我
Mr. Song...
宋先生...
I've been
investigating you for months.
我调查你已经好几个月了
I know everything about you.
你的底细我一清二楚
Listen, my friend back there
wants his little girl back.
听着 我后面这位朋友想找回他的女儿
So if you don't talk...
所以如果你不开口...
(EXHALES)
...the whole world is
gonna know who you are,
全世界都会知道你是谁
and how you make your money.
以及你的钱是怎么赚来的
(INHALES)
Even if we let you live...
就算我们留你一命...
you won't last long.
你也活不长
What are you?
你算什么东西？
A reporter? Huh? (CHUCKLES)
记者吗？
You know what happened
to the last bitch
你知道上一个自称是记者的臭婊子
that said she was a reporter?
下场如何吗？
(SCOFFS) Your kind...
You get in...
你们这种人 总是喜欢
deep over your head, man.
不自量力 老兄
What the fuck did you say?
你他妈说什么？
Is it her?
是她吗？
Tell me
what you know right now.
马上把你知道的都告诉我
I don't know shit.
我什么都不知道
Tell me
what you know about her.
告诉我 关于她的事
I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道...
(WHIMPERS)
I don't know!
我不知道
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- (SCREAMING)
(CRACKLING STOPS)
SONG: I've just
heard about her from
我只是听说了她的事
the guys at the Snake Pit.
听蛇窟的人说的
No one's getting out alive.
没人能活着出来
What the fuck
is the Snake Pit?
蛇窟他妈的是什么地方？
(DISTANT SIREN BLARING)
(IN MANDARIN)
There's no way out.
进来了 就逃不掉了
(RAINY STRAINING)
We won't know unless we try.
不试试怎么知道
Well, don't drag me into it.
你别连累我
If they catch us trying
to escape, they'll torture us to death.
如果他们发现我们要逃 肯定会折磨我们的
(RAINY SPEAKS)
If we don't try, we're dead for sure.
不逃肯定没命
You think I never tried?
Look at my leg!
我试过反抗 结果呢？ 你看我的腿
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
Don't you want to go home?
你不想回家吗？
Don't talk to me about "home".
I've never had one!
别跟我说回家 我没有家
I watched them kill my family.
我最后一个亲人也被他们杀死了
(SOBBING)
If I find a way out,
如果 我找到出路
you can come home with me.
你和我一起走吧
You're crazy.
神经病
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(IN ENGLISH)
Get the boat ready!
把船准备好
I'll be there in half-hour!
我半小时后到
- (ARROW WHOOSHES)
- (GROANING)
Where are you going, Mr. Song?
你去哪儿 宋先生？
I heard something about boats.
You're going to the pier?
我听说什么船 你要去码头吗？
What did you
tell the Chinese mute?
你跟那个中国哑巴说了什么？
(CHUCKLES)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
The freezer truck's
over there.
冷藏车在那边
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Find another way in.
找别的入口
(LIGHTER CLICKING)
(CLATTERS)
(IN MANDARIN) Stop it.
快住手
(DOOR OPENS)
(IN ENGLISH)
I'm checking the kids now.
我正在检查孩子们
Yeah.
是的
(SIGHS)
They're asking
for you, sweetheart.
他们在找你呢 宝贝儿
Come on. Get down here.
过来 给我下来
- (MAN SCREAMS)
- (RAINY GRUNTS)
Go! Go!
走 走
(BOY SPEAKING MANDARIN)
This place is so big!
这里这么大
We can't escape.
跑不掉的
You idiot!
你这个猪头
RAINY: (IN ENGLISH) Go!
走
(DISTANT DOG BARKING)
- (CELL PHONE BEEPS)
- Hello, everyone.
大家好
My name is Navin.
我叫纳文
I've been posting
under Matia's account
过去几个月里我一直在用玛蒂娅的账号发帖
for the last few months.
- (MAN GRUNTING)
- (CHILDREN CLAMORING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING
IN DISTANCE)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
NAVIN: My name is Navin.
我叫纳文
I've been posting
under Matia's account
过去几个月里我一直在用玛蒂娅的账号发帖
for the last few months.
I'm streaming from a location
out on the west side
我正在西区一个地方直播
called the Snake Pit.
这里叫蛇窟
Matia discovered
kidnapped children
玛蒂娅发现被绑架的孩子们
are being held
against their will.
被非法关押在这里
And I think
she's in there, too.
我觉得她也被关在里面
If there's anyone out there
seeing this stream,
如果有人看到这个直播
please share it.
请把它分享出去
We need people on the street
to have any chance
我们需要街头群众的力量 才有可能
of exposing
the men that did this.
揭发做出这种事的罪魁祸首
Sergeant! Sergeant!
Look at this!
警司 警司 快看这个
(MAN GRUNTING ON VIDEO)
Oh, my God!
我的天哪
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(THUG GROANS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸爸
Sorry... I'm so sorry...
对不起...
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBBING)
(IN ENGLISH)
We've gotta get out of here!
我们得离开这里
They're coming!
他们来了
Come on!
快走
(IN MANDARIN)
I want to go back for the other kids.
我想回去救人
There are so many of them...
还有好多小孩...
still in there.
他们都被抓了
They'll be killed
他们会被打死的
and it's all my fault.
都是我的错
You did great, Rainy.
雨晴 你做的很对
Where are they?
他们在哪儿？
Locked in a room upstairs.
被关在上面了
I'll take it from here.
你放心吧 叔叔会去救他们
Just go home,
现在你回家吧
okay?
好吗？
(IN ENGLISH) I'll stay.
我留下来
Your job is done here.
Mine is not.
你的任务完成了 我还没有
(MAN GRUNTING)
NAVIN: Now get her
out of here.
现在带她离开这里
(GRUNTING)
Go!
快走
(PUNCHES LANDING)
(IN FILIPINO)
We've got intruders at the Snake Pit!
蛇窟有闯入者
Send everybody!
把所有人都派过去
- (PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- (SIRENS APPROACHING)
(IN ENGLISH) Where are they?
他们在哪？
Over here!
在这边
This way!
这边
OFFICER: This way!
Yadong!
雅东
What the hell are you doing?
你在这干什么？
Stand down.
退下
There's video of children
being held here.
有视频拍到孩子们被关在这里
I saw it myself.
我亲眼看到的
God damn it!
该死的
Get that stupid idea
out of your head,
把你那些愚蠢的想法收起来
- and clear this street!
- OFFICER: Hey, stop!
-把这条街清场 -嘿 站住
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Stop right there!
站在那别动
Stand aside.
靠边站
Captain, you can't be serious?
队长 你不是认真的吧？
- (CHILDREN SCREAMING)
- (MEN SHOUTING)
an9（和朋友们在一起）
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYS)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(IN FILIPINO) They're upstairs!
他们在楼上
(THUGS GRUNTING)
(IN ENGLISH)
Stay together. We're leaving.
所有人待在一起 我带你们离开这
THUG: Come on!
快点
(CHILDREN SCREAM)
This way.
Over here. Over there!
这边 在这边 在那边
(BANGING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(RAINY GRUNTING)
(BONES CRACK)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(GRUNTING)
(IN MANDARIN)
Uncle! We're here to help you!
叔叔 我们来帮你
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(CHAIN CLINKING)
(YELLS)
(THUGS GRUNTING)
(BONE SNAP)
(PANTING)
(IN MANDARIN)
Some of my friends are still trapped upstairs.
我还有些朋友在上面
I'll take you there.
我带你们去
- (PEOPLE CLAMORING)
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
Rainy. Wait!
雨晴 等等
RAINY: (IN ENGLISH)
Let's go! Go! Hurry! Run!
快走 快走 快点 跑
Go! Go!
走 走
- Watch your step.
- RAINY: Go!
-小心脚下 -走
NAVIN: Stay together!
RAINY: Hurry!
待在一起 快点
(IN MANDARIN)
You already escaped. Why did you come back?
你都已经走了 为什么还要回来？
I don't leave friends behind.
我才不会放弃我的朋友
You don't have a family,
but you can still have friends.
你就算没有家 也可以有朋友
Let's go.
走
NAVIN: Let's go.
快走
(IN MANDARIN)
You really are an idiot!
真是个猪头
You're all idiots!
你们都是猪头
(THUGS GRUNTING)
(ALL PANTING)
(THUGS SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
(GIRL IN FILIPINO)
What should we do?
我们该怎么办？
How do we get down from here?
我们怎么从这里下去？
It's so high!
太高了
(IN ENGLISH) Come on!
快来
Let's use this!
用这个
- Come on!
- (CHILDREN CLAMORING)
快点
(CHILDREN IN FILIPINO)
Tie it tight! Check the knots!
绑紧点 检查一下绳结
Tie it tighter!
绑紧一点
(GRUNTING)
(IN MANDARIN) Ready!
我好了
(ALL CLAMORING)
(IN ENGLISH) Slowly.
慢慢来
(WOMAN IN FILIPINO)
Let us through, we can help!
让我们过去 我们可以帮忙
Why are you just standing there?
Save the kids!
你们为什么光站着？ 快救救孩子们
It's the kids you should
worry about!
你们该担心的应该是那些孩子
(IN ENGLISH) Next one.
下一个
(STRAINING)
(IN MANDARIN) Hurry!
你快点
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
- How can you do nothing?
- You cops are useless!
-你们怎么能无动于衷？ -你们这些警察真是废物
Cowards! Save them!
你们这群懦夫 快去救人啊
- They're just kids!
- What's wrong with you?
-他们只是孩子 -你们怎么回事？
(IN ENGLISH) Squad one
and two, come with me.
一队和二队 跟我来
I told you,
I'm not authorizing this.
我说过 我没有批准行动
You can't deny
what's happening!
你不能对正在发生的事视而不见
Take her away!
把她带走
Sacha! I'm ordering you!
萨沙 这是命令
I heard you!
我听到了
Sergeant.
警司
CAPTAIN: Yadong!
雅东
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Cover the exit!
守住出口
Follow me!
This way, this way! Come on!
跟我来 这边 这边 快跟上
(STRAINING, GASPS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
- (GROANS)
- (YELPS)
(IN MANDARIN)
Come on. Your turn!
喂 快点 到你了
You go!
快走
You saved me. I owe you one!
你之前救了我 算我还你
Go!
快走
See you outside!
下面等我
Go now!
快走啊
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(FLESH SQUELCHING)
(THUGS SHOUTING)
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (RIPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAM)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(BOY SPEAKING) Rainy!
雨晴
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
I'm okay!
我没事
(GASPS)
- (THUDDING)
- (THUGS SHOUTING)
(THUG SCREAMS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Watch out!
小心
(GUNSHOT)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(IN ENGLISH) Freeze!
不许动
Drop your weapons!
Drop it now!
放下武器 马上放下
(BOTH PANTING)
(MAN IN FILIPINO)
We need a medic. Help the kids!
我们需要医护人员 快救孩子们
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Don't be afraid, kid.
You're safe now.
别怕 孩子 你现在安全了
MAN 2: (IN ENGLISH)
That's what you get, asshole!
这是你罪有应得的 人渣
MAN 3: Get him
the hell off our streets!
把他从我们的街上轰出去
Officer.
警官
Did you guys find this woman
inside the building?
你们在大楼里找到这个女人了吗？
She's the journalist
whose work led us here.
她就是那个查出线索 带我们找到这的记者
Mm-mm.
没有
- (DISTANT SIRENS WHOOPING)
- (POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
Unrest broke out earlier
早些时候发生了骚乱
when police responded
to the live-stream rescue
当时警方正在响应一场被直播的救援行动
of dozens
of trafficked children
解救数十名被拐卖的儿童
from a westside
district building
地点位于西区的一栋大楼内
owned by local tycoon
Kun Tai Luo.
该大楼隶属于当地富豪 罗坤泰
The company's issued
a statement to the press
该公司已向媒体发表声明
promising
a thorough investigation
承诺将进行彻底调查
- on how the leased building--
-  (CELL PHONE RINGING)
查明这栋被出租的大楼是如何...
Yes?
什么事？
I'll be right there.
我马上过去
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
My daddy's looking for you.
我爸爸在找你
All of his partners are here.
What's going on?
他的合伙人都在这 出什么事了？
Everything is fine.
一切都好
I'll see you in our room.
在房间里等我
(DOOR CLOSES)
You wanted to see me, sir?
您找我 先生？
MAN: The Captain is here
to take you into custody.
警监是来拘留你的
We all need to save face.
大家都要顾全点面子
As one father to another...
作为人父的我...
you disgust me.
你让我恶心
If it were guns or drugs,
I would understand.
如果是贩卖枪支或毒品 我还能理解
But children?
但是拐卖儿童？
So, when I make you money,
I'm family,
所以 我帮你赚钱的时候 就是一家人
but when shit hits the fan...
但一旦出了乱子
I disgust you?
我就让你恶心了？
Boss, I told you
this kid was trouble!
老板 我早就说过这小子是个麻烦
Now we're left
to clean up your mess!
现在还得我们来给你收拾烂摊子
- (CRUNCHES)
- (SCREAMING)
- (CONTINUES SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
Hey! Are you crazy? (SCREAMS)
嘿 你疯了吗？
Let me go! I'm a cop, damn it!
别碰我 我是警察 妈的
(SCREAMING)
(SQUELCHING)
I brought you into my home!
我把你带进家门
I gave you my daughter!
我把女儿都交给了你
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(STABS)
(SQUELCHING)
(GROANING)
(MEN GASP)
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
- (SLASHES)
- (WOMAN WHIMPERS)
(GASPING)
Why?
为什么？
Why? (GROANS)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(LOW OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SEETHING)
(YELLS LOUDLY)
(DISTANT SIREN BLARING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Sergeant. Coffee.
警司 咖啡
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Wang,
here's your statement.
王先生 这是您的口供
If there aren't any issues,
sign at the bottom.
如果没什么问题 就在最下面签字
I can testify that you acted
in self-defense.
我可以作证你是出于自卫
But I can't
officially release you
但我不能正式释放你走
until you've been
granted bail,
必须等到你获准保释才行
which may not be
until tomorrow morning.
可能要到明天早上了
I hope you understand.
希望你能理解
We'll look after
your daughter.
我们会照顾好你女儿的
You don't have parents?
你没有父母吗？
Who are you, really?
你到底是谁？
I'm just a father.
我只是一个父亲
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Father...
爸爸
(SOBBING)
(WIND WHISTLES)
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
- (GATE OPENS)
(GATE UNLOCKS)
- (KEYS JINGLING)
- (EXHALES)
NAVIN: Hey...
嘿
We saved a lot of kids today.
我们今天救了很多孩子
All because
you chose to come back.
这都归功于你选择了回来
Thank you.
谢谢你
(SIGHS) My wife called
the night she disappeared.
我妻子失踪那晚 给我打过电话
We had an argument
and she walked out.
我们吵了一架 然后她就走了
I wanted to leave
this country for good.
我本想永远离开这个国家的
Find somewhere safe.
Raise our own family.
找个安全的地方 养育我们自己的家庭
Basically, to save ourselves.
说白了 就是为了自保
(CHUCKLES) She was obsessed
她却一心想要
with finding
all these missing kids.
找到所有这些失踪的孩子
I had no idea
how close she was
我完全不知道她离真相有多近
until after she was gone.
直到她不在了才知道
So, when I find her someday...
所以 等哪天我找到她了...
I hope she can forgive me.
我希望她能原谅我
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Nice work today.
今天干得漂亮
Do I get a promotion?
那我能升职吗？
(CHUCKLES)
(IN MANDARIN) Let's go home.
我们回家吧
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Boss.
老板
Five minutes.
给我五分钟
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(OFFICERS GROANING)
(MUFFLED CLATTERING)
(GATE OPENS)
NAVIN: Hey.
嘿
- (RATTLING)
- Hey!
嘿
(SIGHS) God, I'll be glad
when this renovation's done.
天哪 真希望这装修能尽快弄完
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Let me go check
the breaker box.
我去检查一下配电箱
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(COCKS GUN)
- (SCREAMS)
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
(YELPS)
- (SLASHING)
- (GROANING)
(COUGHS)
(GROANING)
(WHEEZING)
(COUGHS, GROANS)
- (ARROW WHISTLES)
- (GROANS)
(GROANING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(QUIETLY) Don't make a sound.
别出声
My father...
我爸爸
I'll check on him.
我去看看他
For now, just stay quiet
and don't go anywhere, okay?
现在 你就乖乖待着别出声 哪儿也别去 好吗？
(TWO GUNSHOTS UPSTAIRS)
NAVIN: The key!
钥匙
Try to reach it.
够一下试试
(STRAINING)
(GUNSHOT UPSTAIRS)
Hold on. Hold on.
坚持住 坚持住
(STRAINING)
Keep pushing.
继续推
(STRAINING)
(WINDSHIELD WIPERS THUDDING)
(GROANING)
(ARROW TAPS ON BOW,
BOW STRING CREAKS)
Stop!
住手
(GROANS)
I said, "Stop!"
我说“住手”
Put down your weapon!
放下武器
(GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(NAVIN GROANING)
(SNAPS FINGERS TWICE)
(IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸
(IN ENGLISH) Ah,
you must be the Chinese mute.
啊 你一定就是那个中国哑巴
Finally.
终于见面了
You know,
I was going to be a father?
你知道吗？ 我本来也要当爸爸了
But you guys
took that away from me.
但你们剥夺了我这个权利
- (OFFICER GRUNTS)
- (RAINY GASPS)
(FLESH SQUELCHING)
(GRUNTING)
(IN MANDARIN) Go! Go.
走 走走走
Hurry!
快
(RAINY SCREAMS)
Go!
走
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(RAINY BREATHING HEAVILY)
(STRAINING)
(RAINY GROANING)
(BROKEN ARROW CLATTERS)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(YELLING)
(EERIE VOCALIZATION PLAYS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
(IN ENGLISH)
You killed Father! You!
你杀了爸爸 你个混蛋
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(HO YELLING)
(DRAMATIC STING PLAYS)
PAKLUNG: Your "father"?
你“爸爸”？
Seriously?
认真的吗？
Did you really think
你真的以为
that fucking cowboy
was your father?
那个傻子牛仔是你爸爸吗？
(PAKLUNG CHUCKLES)
You weren't his son.
你不是他儿子
Get that
through your thick skull!
用你那榆木脑袋好好想想
No! Father said--
不 爸爸说
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
You're evil!
你们这些恶魔
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
- (GROANING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(GROANING)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
- (STABS)
- (GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(TINKLING)
- (METAL CLATTERS)
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
(WHEEZES)
Oh, that reporter...
哦 那个记者
Did you give her this ring?
这戒指是你给她的吗？
Such beautiful eyes...
多美的眼睛啊
She died very slowly.
她死得很痛苦
(NAVIN GROANS)
You want this?
想要这个吗？
Take it back.
来拿回去啊
Come on. Come on.
来啊 来啊
- (YELLS)
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
(GRUNTING)
- (CLANGS)
- (GROANING)
(SLASHING)
- (GRUNTS)
(SQUELCHING)
(GROANING)
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (COUGHS WEAKLY)
(YELLS)
(ROARS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHS)
(WEAKLY) My friend...
朋友
I found her.
我找到她了
I found...
我找到...
(CLINKS)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(SCREAMING)
Now you'll know how it feels
to see your daughter die.
现在你知道 看着女儿死是什么滋味了
All this pain and suffering--
所有痛苦和煎熬...
(YELLS)
(IN MANDARIN)
Rainy, are you okay?
雨晴 你没事吧？
(IN ENGLISH)
This is your fate.
这就是你的命
Accept it.
接受现实吧
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
- (BONE CRUNCHES)
- (SCREAMS)
(YELLING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(GRUNTING)
(SQUELCHING)
(IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸
(PUNCHES LANDING)
Enough! Don't fight anymore!
够了 不要再打了
Dad!
爸
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GROANING)
- Dad!
- Uncle!
-爸 -叔叔
Dad!
爸
Uncle.
叔叔
We'll practice kung fu together!
我们一起练功夫
Wake up!
醒醒
Don't go to sleep!
不能睡
(BOY SPEAKS)
Uncle, wake up! Don't die!
叔叔 快醒醒 别死啊
(PAKLUNG PANTING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(RETCHES)
Mirai...
米莱
(IN ENGLISH)
I've got to go home.
我得回家了
I've got to get back
to my wife and daughter.
我得回到妻子和女儿身边去
(GROANS)
Hey... See you.
嘿 再见
(CHUCKLES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Mirai...
米莱
(IN MANDARIN) Dad!
爸
- Uncle.
- Dad!
-叔叔 -爸
Dad!
爸
(SOBBING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(WAVES SPLASHING)
（一个月后）
(TINKLING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
（纪念纳文和玛蒂亚）
NAVIN: We brought down
the entire trafficking ring.
我们捣毁了整个拐卖团伙
I still don't even
know your name.
我还不知道你叫什么名字呢
(CHUCKLING)
My mysterious friend.
我神秘的朋友
Wang
王
Wei
伟
(CHUCKLES)
Hmm. (CHUCKLES)
嗯
(CAPTIVATING MUSIC PLAYING)
NAVIN: If you're brave enough
to change yourself...
如果你有勇气改变自己..
you can change the world.
你就能改变世界
Wang Wei.
王伟
You look very pretty.
你看起来很漂亮
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAINY IN MANDARIN) Dad.
爸
Will you tell me
your story now?
你可以跟我讲讲你的故事吗？
When I first met your mother...
当我第一次遇见你妈妈时...
( MUDHOLE BY FLYING LOTUS)
♪ Mudhole - Flying Lotus ♪
* If I feel a little alone
♪ 如果我感到有些孤单 ♪
* Bitch
♪ 贱人 ♪
* Don't spit it out
♪ 别吐出来 ♪
- * Bitch
- * Little snake
-♪ 贱人 ♪
-♪ 小蛇 ♪
* Don't spit it out
♪ 别吐出来 ♪
- * Bitch
- * Little snake
-♪ 贱人 ♪
-♪ 小蛇 ♪
* Nigga blessed with the game
♪ 黑哥们受尽这圈子的眷顾 ♪
* Don't know his name
♪ 却无人知晓他的大名 ♪
* Roll through the club
with his gold chain
♪ 戴着大金链子横扫夜店 ♪
* Maintain things on the block
♪ 掌控着街区的一切 ♪
* Rep the whole game
♪ 扛起整个圈子的大旗 ♪
* Everything swing low wise
like an old man
♪ 万事低调行事 犹如老者般睿智 ♪
* Old man old man
I'm in the cabana
♪ 老家伙 老家伙 我身在海滩小屋 ♪
* Rockin' Dolce Gabbana
Smoke marijuana
♪ 穿着杜嘉班纳 抽着大麻 ♪
* Blaze with the blunts
and the bottle
♪ 卷烟配着烈酒 燃爆全场 ♪
* I bring the heat
If you want it
♪ 只要你想 我就能带来狂热火力 ♪
* Get it, Bitch
♪ 懂了吗？ 贱人 ♪
* Don't just spit it out
♪ 别就这么吐出来 ♪
* Shakin' the spot
with the cash in my hand
♪ 手握大把钞票 嗨翻全场 ♪
* I needed to front
like a need an advance
♪ 需要充充场面 假装要预支酬劳 ♪
* Did it to do it
but never mistaken
♪ 想做就做 绝无失手 ♪
* I did it for bands
Uh-uh
♪ 我这么做是为了钞票 嗯哼 ♪
- * Better check on your man
- * Go
-♪ 最好管好你的男人 ♪
-♪ 上 ♪
* Go
♪ 上 ♪
* Big boots like a mudhole
♪ 大靴子踩烂泥坑 ♪
* Watch it watch it
♪ 看着点 看着点 ♪
- * Big boots like a mudhole
- * Little Little Snake
-♪ 大靴子踩烂泥坑 ♪
-♪ 小小蛇 ♪
* Watch it watch it, ya
♪ 看着点 看着点 呀 ♪
* Big boots like a mudhole
♪ 大靴子踩烂泥坑 ♪
* Watch, watch, watch
Watch it, watch it
♪ 小心 小心 看着点 看着点 ♪
- * Big boots like a mudhole
- * Little Little Snake, ya
-♪ 大靴子踩烂泥坑 ♪
-♪ 小小蛇 ♪
* Little Little Snake, ya *
♪ 小小蛇 呀 ♪
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)